Wait, can you hear me now? Oh,
there we go. That's got the OK, yes.
I'm gonna have some things.
OK, so actually turn this mic.
Hello, tell me, tell me.
What?
I put the microphone on the microphone.
Perfect. Excellent. OK.
I'm recording.
I'm gonna probably cut the first like
minute or so off.
This is an informed consent form.
I'm gonna need you to go through it,
make sure that you agree on camera,
so you can verify that you are okay with
getting your data processed by me.
Um...
Mhm.
Basically,
it's just making sure that you know what
you're getting into.
You're getting into an interview about
your study habits.
And you can withdraw at any time up until
the point where I anonymize your data and
then it's anonymized.
Like it won't ever be tied back to you.
Don't worry about it. Sure.
Send [redacted] a quick e-mail telling him
we're running by 10 minutes late.
Shall I sign the next page? Yeah,
please put your name participant
signature dates.
And then your e-mail address,
like your city e-mail address is fine.
Perfect,
there is the 8th of 26 configuration.
OK, love you. Thank you so much,
and I hope I think about myself then.
He didn't think,
but did you tell [redacted] to bring your
laptop with him? If he doesn't have one,
it's fine,
but ideally it would be nice for you,
but it's fine, no big deal.
I have other strategies that I can do. OK,
don't worry about it. So,
this is a semi-structured interview,
so we're gonna let you drift a little bit,
have your own sort of like...
responses to these questions,
but I'm going to try and keep you on
track if that's okay with you. Sure.
So I'm sure you read the brief that I am
here to interview you about how your
study, how your study habits are,
and don't worry about overrunning.
This can last like 20 minutes,
give or take, maybe a little bit more.
Don't worry about that.
If there's something where you're like
rambling and I feel like it's not helpful,
I will let you know so we can keep you on
track.
But I just want to hear like kind of your
unfiltered thoughts, right?
You signed the consent form,
but also you are allowed to say,
I don't want to answer that if there's a
question that I ask.
that you don't want to answer,
you're within your rights.
This will be transcribed.
I'm going to take a few notes just so I
can have like a little bit of context for
myself when it comes to like your actual
modules because there are many things
that I have no clue about and I want to
be able to.
impression with that, right?
So now that I've completed that,
we can get it started.
So we're gonna start really easy.
What modules together did you do this
semester? So semester two.
We have mechatronics.
And we have...
Design, design engine,
which is basically digital design as well.
OK, we have.
See.
We have engineering society,
but it's like an ethics market. Yeah,
we have.
This is taking a while to get to my mind.
Oh, sensors and instrumentation,
that's one major one.
Who is the company?
Oops, yeah, we have data analysis as well,
data analysis.
So, it's just these few that I make, well,
different assess, mechatronics,
sensor systems, instrumentation,
data and engineering design,
and engineering society. OK, yeah,
seems like a normal course load,
would you say? Yes, cool.
Do you want to rank them,
like how difficult they are,
one through 5?
Oh.
Mechatron cell probably rates as one of
the highest, so the hardest, the hardest,
sure. OK, now go ahead.
And then we could say engineering design.
OK.
And then we have census systems. OK,
we have that is data analysis,
then census system. OK, yeah,
and then the last one is just engine
society. OK, so one through 5,
one is the toughest, you would say. Yes,
OK. What do you do in mechatronics?
So I have no context on this,
so just give me a little bit about...
Mechatronics is just a module where we
encounter various systems like pneumatic
systems, hydraulic systems,
and then we learn about those sorts of
systems and we move on to...
So, do you do fluid model?
Is that why it's tough, or no, really?
That's probably for like the mechanics,
right? Okay, yes,
but now once we just did,
there's also control control, so yeah,
a bit of control, and why is that?
Is that because it's like maths heavy,
physics heavy? It's a mix of both.
So it's math and physics? Yes. Okay. So...
Is it also because you have to?
I guess.
Compared to the real world,
or the first part of it was interesting.
The part where we worked on pneumatic
systems,
I thought it was interesting because it
was linked to the real world,
but the latest stuff we did was more
complicated,
like the control systems part.
And is it because it's more theoretical
or? It's more theoretical.
Tse.
Oh,
so system system modelling was a
different, was a difficult one.
That was the most important because that
was a theoretical. Right, okay.
And when we had ordinary differential
equations, yes,
so such as it made it more difficult
because it was also focused on...
free and forced vibration stuff,
which is not relevant that much to my
course,
was with more like electronics focus. Yes,
I guess it felt more like a mechanical
engineering. Yes, exactly. Right,
I understand. OK, cool.
I'm going to go into the big overarching
topics now. Sure.
Do you structure your day when you're
like studying, working, going to the gym,
doing various things, cooking, cleaning?
Do you have like a schedule that you
adhere to? No. Okay, yeah, that's fine.
But what I do is normally from the time
between 9.
No, between like 8 to like...
Eleven o'clock I spent my time like going
through the content and did that.
That's the only time of the day that I've
structured.
Eight to 11 in the morning or evening?
In the evening. Right, okay.
So like the night before the classes.
You block out your evenings to look at
the upcoming or previous?
Depends on the module. Some lectures,
they upload the stuff.
In the morning,
we don't get to look at the...
Set slides before the lecture, so...
For the sessions that they are uploaded
before, like the night before, yeah,
I look at those, you would say I pre-read,
or I just review the ones. OK, yeah,
that makes sense. I mean,
that sounds like you've actually
structured it, to be honest. So,
how do you prioritise your modules?
Is it just you do the ones that you've
got in the upcoming day?
What happens if you got?
two lectures in one day.
I just prioritise the one which is more
difficult. Right, okay, that makes sense.
Yeah. So if I have...
Like.
Because it hasn't occurred to me,
because most of the days it's just one
module, one lecture per day.
That makes sense. Unless it's a tutorial.
Let's say you have exams, right? Yes.
Do you give more time to more difficult
modules?
So, no, I just do an order of, like,
which one? OK, yeah,
'cause into the exams I've done,
sort of the hardest one, you normally...
Um...
When you only read the first ones,
so you're spending all your time on that,
then you transfer. Yeah, that makes sense.
Sure. Do you,
would you say you revise it differently
per module? Like, do you do, for instance,
reading just Moodle notes,
doing like work examples,
sometimes there's like tutorials, do you?
Per module, of course, like, for instance,
mechatronics and design engineering
design.
Engineering design is just coursework,
so there's no exams for that,
and that's an engineering society,
there's no exams for that, so it's not.
Yeah, no,
I'm talking about just revision here.
Yeah, revision. There's not much revision.
Sure, okay. For that. Yeah,
that makes sense. For the exam system,
I mean, yeah,
whereas we talked about like just prior,
like the night before, yeah. Oh, yes,
I looked at the...
the slides mainly and that they have the
tutorials because there's some key parts
in the slides that don't come up in. Yeah,
that makes sense. All right, yeah.
Do you have your studying materials
easily accessible when you study?
Like Moodle, GM, or textbooks? Like,
are they easy to access, would you say?
Yes,
they are the easiest access because most
of them are online. So yeah,
do you get extra like materials like say
from Google?
If you search for extra materials for
let's say your mechatronics,
do you look for additional worksheets,
additional explanations?
YouTube videos are fine.
Yes, you should be right. OK, yeah, well,
I do, apart from that,
I also look at back at some lecture
capture, yeah, OK, yeah,
that's really good, like sure capture,
whatever, yeah, that's great.
Do you use any other applications to help
study, like other than YouTube, Moodle,
and what's lecture capture?
Other than those.
I might just like occasionally guess like
A.I. to summarize, yeah, that was perfect,
yeah, the lectures,
and like explain and like sample words,
sometimes I think this is sound A.I.
some reason.
Do you get into Quizzy?
Um...
This,
this part mainly goes for the exam season,
when I, yeah, I use Notes L, Notes LM,
Notebook LM, yeah, okay,
now that I use that for quiz for creating
quizzes. This is helpful,
because this is here, okay, yeah,
how effective would you say the tools are?
What would you say is?
Do you wanna rank them?
Are YouTube videos helpful,
lecture captures? Yeah,
so the whole helpful is lecture captures
are good for if I want to go back to if I
miss something like on the whiteboard or
yeah, okay, yeah,
or something that the lecturer has
explained in that sense it is useful, but.
..
Majority of the time I'm just using the
Moodle.
Slides, yeah, makes sense. Yeah, OK, cool.
Another thing you could add probably for
the resources is notion, notion.
I use notion to create the note,
like store the notes, separate notion,
but the notebook, just to create the quiz.
Yeah, that makes sense. OK.
Yeah, solid. Okay, so little,
we have discussed a little bit,
we've discussed a little about your
structure for studying,
but now I want to talk about like your
study environment.
So this would be like within your home at
your desk, right?
Yeah,
I think you're smiling in a weird way.
Let's talk a little bit about what makes
a good study space versus a bad study
space.
Now, this is really open-ended.
The.
What I've experienced was if I was
sitting like in the living room,
I might get it and it's an open plan
living room.
I normally get distracted because like
people like my mum, for example,
do like the house strolls,
like cleaning and stuff like that.
So it gets,
it distracts me a bit because of like the
movement that's happening. Yeah,
just people.
Yeah, sure.
I normally see that the times that I want
to focus really well,
I'll just go to the bedroom and just walk
there where there's minimal like movement
within the room. So movement is a big one.
Yes.
What about having like the television on
when you're studying?
Does that distract you?
Not really, because I normally have that,
right? So, you're blocking out the sound,
sound is another distraction, right? I,
I hear it, but even if I'm not listening,
sometimes I just have one headphone that
also.
And then it has some effect on me to like
focus on it when I just have one.
What about like clutter in your study
space, like a bunch of stuff on your desk?
Does that affect your studying negatively,
would you say?
Ohh.
I mean, I get it.
I normally don't have much.
You keep your desk clean. Okay, awesome.
Okay, so yeah,
like you've already answered this next
question.
Do you find yourself more productive in
one place? You do, it's in your bedroom.
Do you study like at uni as well,
like for instance in the library?
In like a third space, um,
during like the times I have between my
my lectures and you have some tutorials,
I...
I tried to go and use the silence,
study space, and the like, yeah, OK, yeah,
OK,
so that's so I guess silence and lack of
distraction is like really important for
your studying, sure, yeah,
and then if it's a very sensitive course,
like let's say it's something I have to.
Deeply understand, so, like, mechatronics,
you would say you're taught this one,
for instance? Yes, or, like,
when I just study for like some, like,
key exam, I need to understand it.
It's like the pneumatic systems,
the hydraulic systems,
which isn't that difficult to understand.
Sure,
I'll just work with work in the living
room, yeah.
That makes sense.
If it's like something stressful, like,
because for the engineering design
projects,
which I needed to really focus on, yeah,
the...
Linking the past together then.
The project.
I need it to be in an assignment space
work. Yeah, that makes sense. So, like,
how do you guarantee like the silence
lack of distraction? Here in the library,
it's a social cue that you're not meant
to make noise, right?
If you're studying in your room,
do you ask your family to make less noise
when they know you're studying or?
It's just me and my mom, so she's,
whenever she sees me walking,
she's really quiet. It's kind of unspoken.
Even in the living room, she's quiet,
but it's just a nice. Yeah, I got that.
I understand.
Is it difficult to get everything set up
to study? Would you say?
Would you say that you have like a ritual?
Need to prepare yourself to study,
or can you just like sit down,
open your laptop, and start working?
It's easy.
I can only do when I've like decluttered
my mind, right?
And like I've settled down a bit.
So you need to be in a studying mindset,
you would say. I need to be like restive.
So like I've gone,
but that's one of the reason I start
working like late in the day,
like 8 to 11.
Commute from uni to eat and that's all.
Expert context that you know. Yeah,
that makes sense. Okay, cool.
Would you say that you get distracted
often when you're studying?
Yes. Yeah, you get context switches.
I mean, that's totally fine.
What would you say your biggest
distractions are?
Really just trying to keep up with like
the currents of them. Sure,
I understand extra context everyone. Yeah,
sure.
About like a question follow up: Is there
something you do to remedy this,
but there's not really something you can
do to remedy this, unless, unless...
I'm more stressed about the project that
I'm doing that I completely forget about.
Yeah, okay, fair enough. Yeah.
I forcefully blocked the...
So let's talk about your actual study
session itself,
like when you're in the active study.
When you do your studies,
do you work alone or with others? Like,
do you study with people, for instance,
like on a Teams call or a Discord call,
or do you do like asynchronous
communication with teammates?
Because I know you have a decent amount
of group projects.
We do for revision during the exam season,
like probably like we can say three days
before, two days before, those three days,
two days,
we spend like joining a Discord poll and
then we would just go through reviewing
everything together.
So like someone would share the screen.
Each of us tried to answer it, or, like,
one person tried to solve that,
and we tried to, like,
see what the problem is that they're
going through. That's the exam season.
Other than that, projects,
we were more active like last year,
being on voice,
but now we just delegate the tasks. Yeah,
sure. Yeah, that's fine.
Do you also do studies on your own?
I presume yes. OK, so you've done both.
Do you prefer to do it with like?
Other people like,
do you like those Discord calls where you
go through questions and point out issues?
I like it if there's lots of people don't
come in and distract because it's a sub,
right? OK, yeah,
people if people come in and cause
distraction or like someone goes off
topic, so talking that will.
Cause disruption,
that's why I normally attend very few of
those right sessions. I mean,
when those like distractions put you off,
that makes sense, yeah,
and like they go at a slower pace than I
would, yeah, want to go.
Do you get to study in your ideal
environment often?
Yes, yes, that makes sense.
Do you like to snack while you do
something like eat?
Um...
If it's not stressful,
if there's not a course that I have to
deeply focus on, right,
then I'm so you'd say for like your data
analysis, sensors,
and engineering society, you'd be,
for instance,
eating crisps while reading the slides,
or yes, it's unlike I rarely do it, but I.
..
Sometimes, so you don't prefer to.
I prefer not to. Sure, that makes sense.
Yeah,
because I've got follow-ups for that,
but that's OK. Don't worry about it. So,
yeah, when you study with others,
you mentioned like being in the Discord
server.
How do you coordinate like times to do
these revisions? Do you have like,
for instance, a ping at everyone?
We're going to be revising X module and Y
minutes,
or is it kind of just free flow whoever
joined us joins?
Um...
We normally start revision like one, two,
three, one, two, okay,
three to two days before the exam. Yeah,
that's right.
So normally all of us would be studying
for the same course. Yes, that's right.
It'll be like, yes, it would be like,
who wants to join?
Who wants to join for revision?
Whoever wants to join. Yeah,
do you schedule that? Do you say like,
I'm going to do some revision in an hour,
who wants to join? Or is it just like,
I'm studying now, join now? Or? Oh,
it's completely random. It's random. OK,
sure, spontaneous. That's fine. Yeah. OK,
I want you to share your screen now. Yeah.
And I want you to...
Walk me through a typical one of your
study sessions. Thank you.
Yes.
Ohh no, shares that, yes.
Yeah.
Uh, test screen.
Yeah.
Sure. Then this is in my actual.
This is in my actual setup,
which I have at home. So yeah,
but we're just going to like lay the
scene out for me.
You're at home right now. Yes.
You've chosen to study, I'm guessing,
in your bedroom. Yes. Sure. OK.
And you set up your study time in the
evening, like you've already described.
Sure.
Let's say you want to study one of your
tougher modules. What would you do?
How would you set up your desktop
environment for that?
Would you open up Moodle?
Would you split screen it?
You can demonstrate on the computer if I
want to. I need to open up Moodle.
I'll try.
For some, I'll go for...
No, they haven't put this.
I'll just open this. Yeah,
I would like to open this.
Okay, no, that's fine.
Don't worry about that. It's fine. Well,
I'll first like open this up.
I'll like look through it.
And then as soon as I don't understand,
I'll just download the solutions.
And if I don't understand it,
I instantly cheque that question instead
of like, it is my first time doing it.
I'll attempt that question and then right
afterwards cheque the solutions for it in
the solutions platform.
Are the solutions worked normally?
Like are there step-by-step solutions for
them?
Or is it sometimes just an answer and you
have to deduce the working steps?
In this case,
they're going to give us the solutions.
Until, like, after the tutorial session,
yeah, that makes sense. So, like,
they do give us solutions,
but not the worst solution. So,
for example,
you have like short answers at the end,
which is, for example, 560 kg for maths.
Well, that's not great, to be honest,
right? This is the solution we get at.
Ohh, very good, but then we have a worked,
so you got work solutions after. Sure,
that makes sense. Yeah,
so we've chosen a tough topic,
mechatronics. When you're doing this,
would you say that you've ever called
like another person doing the same course
for like help?
on some of the questions in the tutorials.
But.
Not many of the people I know attended,
right? I see. Um,
would you say other people ask you for
help?
They have,
and this could be for any module, yes,
not specifically mechatronics.
Um...
Not really, no.
Most of the questions I start asking is
when they reach like the exam system.
Right, I see, that makes sense. Yeah, so.
Well, sorry, well,
I do sometimes like put the file out
saying this is a really difficult like
tutorial, we should try and work on it.
Yeah, that makes sense.
No one was at, that makes sense, sure. Um,
yeah,
would you say that your study sessions in
the evening are?
I guess.
Good, like, show me,
show me what you would normally do.
Let's say you're making flashcards for an
exam right now.
Show me how you would do that,
just like on your computer, please. So,
I don't, I don't make flash,
but like you plug them into notebook,
I plug,
I plug into notebook LM and I just
generate quizzes, that's.
Sure, we have that first,
if you wouldn't mind.
'Cause I'm very curious about the actual
user flow here. I'll make,
I'll show you what I did previously. Yeah,
that's totally fine. Yeah, we have here.
It, it's done a few nodes,
and then we have a BJT quiz. OK,
how did you get the sources in?
I uploaded that as much.
I wanted to do it for data analysis.
I was yesterday.
You can show me how that's done.
Just go to the things,
'cause there's an old I downloaded them
mostly on the my, yeah, so sorry, no,
it's fine, I will.
Very quickly.
OK, so probability to.
Number is.
Control S.
Yeah.
One is fine, because I, I,
what I do is normally I would take this
and combine it with like the tutorial
version, right? That makes sense. OK,
yeah, but I can,
I'll just test it with this,
that'll be fine.
upload files.
And then I'm guessing it takes the notes
and it turns them into flashcards,
or sort of, or if you pick it,
because there's an option on these sides,
tool, yes.
I bumped into her by accident,
like before,
when I was trying to find the best
alternative to notion. So,
here you're doing like Bayes theorem,
I guess. Yes, yes,
so then we do like quiz.
Oh wow, yeah.
And then you generate the level of
difficulty. Wow, that's such a cool tool.
Like genuinely. If I have any exams,
I would be doing this. Wait,
so you haven't seen this before or? Never.
I've never used Note the column.
But have you heard that before?
The name rings a bell,
but I've never like looked at it,
looked at it. This is a cool tool.
Thank you for showing me this is.
This started from like this, yes,
so you just use it last semester,
but this,
or like the exams for last semester,
I guess. Yes, I,
I used the exams for last.
Do you think it helped?
Do you think you were more successful?
Um...
It wasn't,
I don't think it was a that advanced back
then. Sure, so it's gotten better.
I haven't used it yet. Sure.
To see how it's different,
but the fact that you can choose a
difficulty, I don't think we had. Okay,
super small.
So it could just stay on probability quiz
and then you have the options there.
Ohh, yeah, that's awesome.
It's like I can just run and pick that.
Ohh, that's yeah, and I told you why. OK,
yes, so useful. OK, cool. Alright, well,
thank you for your time and participation.
Is there anything more that you'd like to
add that we haven't covered regarding
your studies?
No, not really,
but apart from the fact that...
The lecture capture,
would it have been good if some of the
lectures would would have like moved the
camera to show the one of for one of the
modules,
which is the only one I've seen for
design, you can move the, so, hey,
on person, you can move the camera.
Or,
I'll just show the board 'cause sometimes
it actually,
because he went through the same stuff.
Yes, so alright, thanks very much.
I'm gonna stop the recording.